Guide to the Norman Hurd Ricker Papers, 1916-1978 MS 398
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Norman Hurd Ricker Papers
1916-1978
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Ricker, Norman Hurd, 1896-1980
MS 398
12 Linear Feet (23 boxes)
The Ricker Papers include the notes and papers related to physicist Norman Hurd Ricker's work in industrial research and in his academic career. The 25 boxes contain Ricker's autobiography, published papers, photographs depicting his experience at Rice University and many of his field expeditions, as well as notes, calculations, and graphs in various media, used in his research and writing.
Biographical Note
Norman Hurd Ricker (1896-1980) was raised in Galveston and Albany, Texas, and was a member of Rice's first freshman and first graduating class. After receiving his doctorate in 1920 (the first given in Physics by Rice), Ricker remained at the Institute for a year before leaving to pursue his career in industrial research, first at Western Electric (1920-1923), and later at Humble Oil Refining Company (1923-1927), Hughes Tool Company (1927-1938), and Carter Oil Company (1938-1959). He ended his career of seismic and geophysical exploration in 1959 to return to academic life, taking a professorship of physics at the University of Oklahoma at Norman (1959-1980). Listed among his inventions are the paper cone loudspeaker and equipment for Texas's first deep oil wells, including the plunger lift pump for drilling. He is the author of numerous articles and a book, Transient Waves in Visco-Elastic Media. See Sallyport, April 1978.
Scope and Contents
The Norman Hurd Ricker Papers, composed of 24 document boxes and one Hollinger box, include the notes and papers related to Ricker's work in industrial research and his academic career. The boxes contain Ricker's autobiography, published papers, photographs depicting his experience at Rice and many of his field expeditions, as well as notes, calculations, and graphs in various media, used in his research and writing. The materials have maintained the structure in which they were received from Ricker's files.
Access Restrictions
There are no accessrestrictions; this material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
The Norman Hurd Ricker Papers were received by Rice from three sources: from Ricker, who gave his Autobiography to the Woodson in May, 1978; from his son, Norman H. Ricker, Jr., who sent a group of photographs in November, 1985; and from his daughter, Florence Ricker Cloudt, who donated six boxes containing notes and papers, many related to Ricker's Wavelet Theory of Seismography, in April, 1986, and two boxes containing glass slides, in December, 1986.
Arrangement
The Norman Hurd Ricker Papers are arranged in four series replicating Ricker's own filing system.
Note that one item in box 24 and all items in box 25 were deaccessioned in August 2009. The remaining items in box 24 were incorporated into box 23.
Missing Title
Series I. Bound and looseleaf notebooks.
Series II. Calculations.
Series III. Wavelet Theory of Seismography.
Series IV. Artifacts and Ephemera.
Index Terms
Subjects
Seismic prospecting; Loudspeakers; Wet wells (Hydraulic engineering); Pumping machinery; Waves; Faculty
Document Types
charts (graphic documents); lecture notes; corrrespondence; notes; photographs; Maps
Subjects (Corporations)
Carter Oil. Jersey Production Research Center.; Hughes Tool Company.; University of Oklahoma.; Western Electric Company.; Humble Oil and Refining Company (Incorporated in Tex.).
- Series I: Looseleaf and Bound Notebooks, 238233
  Scope and Contents note
  Containing graphs, computations, and papers in typescript and Ricker's hand.
  - Looseleaf notebook containing correspondence and notes. Entitled, "A Treatise on the Mathematical Theory of Seismic Prospecting.", c.1947; 238279 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bound notebook containing handwritten notes. Entitled, "Research Notebook No. 1 on the subject of `Our Dual World.'", 17 July 1963; 238278 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bound notebook containing calculations on graph paper. Entitled, "Tabulation of Wavelet Functions and Other Functions Related Thereto.", 238277 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notebook containing graphs and notes grouped topically. Entitled, "Internal Friction Experiments (with torsion tube).", c.1944-1945; 238276 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Notebook containing two papers: May the Stokes Wave Equation Be Universal? and Stokes Wave Equation and the Propagation of a Plane Wave of Sand in a Simple Gas., 238275 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rough draft of a paper entitled, The Propagation of Seismic Wavelets: Chapter I, Historical Introduction., n.d.; 238274 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notebook of computer printouts entitled, Computations of Wavelet Functions, Wavelet Form Functions and Hermite Functions with IBM Card Programme Computer, by Use of Series Development, Plane and Spherical Wave Surfaces., October 1953; 238273 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notebook containing onionskin carbon copies of the first 100 pages of vol. I of the Autobiography of Norman Hurd Ricker., n.d.; 238272 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with the Center for History and Philosophy of Physics, and the American Institute of Physics. Also, notes entitled, General Theory of Wavelet Contraction., c.1964-1971; 238271 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Notebook containing a rough draft of Seismic Wavelets: Being an Account of the Propagation of Transient Disturbances in Visco-Elastic Media., n.d.; 238270 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks containing the fiscal report for the Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratories, Office of Aerospace Research. Entitled, The Propagation of Ultrasonic Elastic Waves in Solid Bodies and in Granular Media., December 1963; 238269 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Reprint of The Form and Laws of Propagation of Seismic Wavelets, comments made on the paper at the Third World Petroleum Congress, and Ricker's replies., c.1951; 238268 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Typewritten copy of a paper by F. P. Murraghan of Johns Hopkins U entitled, On the Finite Deformations of an Elastic Solid., 13 February 1942; 238267 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notebook containing a hand-drawn map of Vietnam, some news-clippings, and Ricker's notes on how tunnels used by the Viet Cong could be located by means of geophysical prospecting methods., 238266 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bound notebook containing notes from a seminar, Wave Propagation and Energy Dissipation. Norman, OK., Sept. 1963; 238265 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Typewritten copy of a paper by Francis A. Collins and C. C. Lee entitled, Seismic Wave Attenuation Characteristics from Pulse Experiments., 238264 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bound handwritten draft of An Introduction to the Mathematical Theory of the Earthwaves Geophysical Prospecting Method., c.1966; 238263 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bound personal diary on Fundamental Seismic Studies, carried out by Party 8: Experimental Seismic Party. Started at Limon, Colo., 10 Sept. 1948; 238262 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Looseleaf notebooks of reviews and correspondence regarding Transient Waves in Visco-Elastic Media., c.1977; 238261 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Looseleaf notebook containing notes on the Interchange of Energy Between Particles as Described by the Stokes Wave Equation., n.d.; 238260 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Looseleaf notebook containing notes and graphs concerning wavelet theory., 238259 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Looseleaf notebook containing notes, graphs, and calculations concerning wavelet theory., 238258 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Reprint from the proceedings of the Third World Petroleum Congress: The Form and Laws of Propagation of Seismic Wavelets., 1951; 238257 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Reprint of A Rational Approach to the Design of Electrical Filters and of Shot-Hole and Geophone Patterns in Seismic Reflection Prospecting, by F. Muir and F. W. Hales., 238256 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Published programs for the Semicentennial and Academic Festival of Rice University. Also, program for the International Conference on Fast Neutron Physics, 10-12 October 1962. 26-28 Feb. 1963; 238255 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bound correspondence regarding The Form and Laws of Propagation of Seismic Wavelets., c.1951-1953; 238254 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Handwritten rough draft of Notes on Gravitation., 238253 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Collection of News Report of the National Academy of Sciences, (vol. VX, no. 1) - (vol. XVIII, no. 2)., Jan. 1965 Feb. 1968; 238252 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Published book: Ultrasonic Imaging. Ed. R. Stuart Mackay. National Academy of Sciences, 1964; 238251 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Notebook containing graphs and notes on theoretical studies and basis for interpretations of the experimental studies now being made on the absorption of supersonic elastic waves in solid bodies and in granular media., 10 Feb. 1962; 238250 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Bound notebook. Entitled, Propagation of a Plane Sound Wave in a Simple Gas., 238249 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten rough draft of the first part of the Autobiography of Norman Ricker (covering the period of his life prior to )., July 1924; 238248 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Bound notebook containing typewritten version of a lecture delivered at the University of Tulsa on Entitled, The Role of Education in this Changing World., 26 October 1966; 238247 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Bound notebook. Entitled, Broad Field of Application of the Stokes Wave Equation., Sept. 1960; 238246 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bound notebook containing rough draft of, May the Stokes Wave Equation Be Universal?, 238245 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bound notebook containing rough draft of, May the Stokes Wave Equation Be Universal?, 238244 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Bound copy of the handwritten rough draft of, An Introduction to the Mathematical Theory of the Earthwaves Geophysical Prospecting Method., 238243 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Bound notebook entitled, A Ring Vortex Theory of Matter and Radiation., 238242 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Bound notebook entitled, Research Notebook `B.', 28 Dec. 1928 - 8 Dec. 1936; 238241 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Bound notebook containing calculations and graphs. Entitled, Notebook of Mathematical Research., 238240 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Notebook containing prints of graphs regarding Wavelet Functions., n.d.; 238239 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Notebook containing prints of graphs regarding Wavelet Functions., n.d.; 238238 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Leaflet about Ricker's book, Transient Waves in Visco-Elastic Media., n.d.; 238237 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Nine reprints of articles by N. Ricker from to, 1941-1953; 238236 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bound notebook containing reprints of articles published by N. Ricker from to [All contained in #44], 1941-1953; 238235 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bound notebook containing reprints of articles published by N. Ricker from to [Some contained in #44], 1916-1953; 238234 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Series II: Calculations, 238002
  Notes for papers and lectures, seismic diagrams, correspondence and memoranda, and patents.
  - Bound notebook containing tabulations. Entitled, Wavelet Functions and Wavelet-Form Functions. Tulsa, OK., 238232 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Notebook diary during the Distinguished Lecture Tour of the Society of Exploration Geophysicists, 22 November 1953 - 20 January 1954; 238231 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten notes for lecture given at Humble Oil laboratories. One of several given between and on Wavelet Theory. Lecture 1., 13 October 17 October, 1947; 238230 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Handwritten notes for lecture given at Humble Oil laboratories. One of several given between and on Wavelet Theory. Lecture 2., 13 October 17 October, 1947; 238229 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Handwritten notes for lecture given at Humble Oil laboratories. One of several given between and on Wavelet Theory. Lecture 3., 13 October 17 October, 1947; 238228 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Handwritten notes for lecture given at Humble Oil laboratories. One of several given between and on Wavelet Theory. Lecture 4., 13 October 17 October, 1947; 238227 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Handwritten notes for lecture given at Humble Oil laboratories. One of several given between and on Wavelet Theory. Lecture 5., 13 October 17 October, 1947; 238226 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Notebook containing a carbon copy of Experimental Studies of the Primary Seismic Disturbance., n.d.; 238225 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Calculations handwritten on large ledger sheets., 13 May 1944; 238224 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Reproductions of graphs dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238223 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Carbon copies of Index of Field Trip `R' Data on Primary Seismic Disturbance., Sept. 1948 - March 1949; 238222 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Carbon copy of the plan for Party 5, Field Trip R., n.d.; 238221 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Reproductions of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238220 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Reproductions of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238219 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Reproductions of graphs dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238218 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Photograph of a geophone with Mousetrap spring mechanism. Limon and Last Chance, Colorado., 238217 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Reproductions of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238216 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Reproductions of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238215 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Reproductions of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238214 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Reproductions of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238213 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Reproductions of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238212 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Reproductions of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238211 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Photographic negative of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238210 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Reproductions of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238209 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Reproductions of diagrams dealing with seismic readings., n.d.; 238208 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Photographs of seismic readings. Mt. Carmel, Utah., n.d.; 238207 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Photographic negatives of graphs and diagrams dealing with seismic readings at Limon and Last Chance, Colorado., 238206 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Materials from which slides were made for a paper sent to the Third World Petroleum Congress: Graphics and Diagrams., 238205 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Reproductions of graphs dealing with seismic readings. Photographic prints: Breakdown of observed forms into wavelet components … Last Chance 3 wavelets in complex., n.d.; 238204 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Photographic negatives of graphs dealing with seismic readings. The Primary Seismic Disturbance in Shale., n.d.; 238203 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Typewritten Table of Contents for a book on wavelets., n.d.; 238202 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence regarding permission to publish., 1976; 238201 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: Notes relative to field trip `R' to Limon and Last Chance, Colo. and to Kanab, Utah for experimental studies of primary seismic disturbance., 238200 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Section of Files entitled, XVI Shooting in Sand. Contains negatives and prints of charts, diagrams, and graphs., 238199 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    General Note
    Items in folder: Pages of calculations. n.d.; Diagrams marked, "Mr. Carmel Utah; Studies in Navajo S. S.; XVI"; Diagrams marked, "Enlargements of Observed forms; Mt. Carmel, Utah Site 8R3; XVI"; Diagrams marked, "8R3 Plates - surface contours - base of L.V.L. contours; and isopach of LVL. Mt. Carmel, Utah prints; XVI"; Diagrams marked, "Geologic Section Site 8R3; Mr. Carmel, Utah; XVI"; Film negative marked, "Geologic Section; Mr. Carmel, Utah; XVI"; Diagrams marked, "travel time; Mr. Carmel, Utah; XVI"; "Cardboard Slides for talk before section meeting Mar. 2, 1950 on proposed studies in dry sand; Shooting in Sand; XVI"; Diagrams marked, "Wavelet Breadth vs. travel time; Mt. Carmel, Utah; Site 8R3"; Film negative marked, "Shooting in Sand; XVI"; Film negative marked, "Mr. Carmel, Utah; XVI"
  - Section of Files entitled, XVII The Nature of Ground Roll. Contains negatives and prints of charts and diagrams., 238198 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Items in folder: Diagrams marked, "Curved Ray Paths and the Herglotz-Bateman integral; XVIII"; Three film negatives marked, "Smaller Negatives; Nature of Ground Roll; XVIII"
  - Section of Files entitled, XIX Composite Reflections. Contains prints of charts and diagrams., 238193 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Items in folder: Papers and maps marked, "Memorandum for File; Composite Reflection Shear Velocity Correction; XIX"; Papers marked, "Composite Reflection Theory; XIX"; Seven Film Negatives marked, "Composite Reflections; Figs. 19.10; XIX"; Film Negative marked, "Composite Reflections; Negative for Fig. 19.1; XIX"
  - Section of Files entitled, XX The Nature of the Low Velocity Layer. Contains negatives and prints of charts and diagrams., 238185 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Items in folder: Notes and graphs marked, "Important Envelope of Data made with Oscillatory Viscosimeter in clay, showing: α proportional to f 2 for large amplitudes; α proportional to f for small amplitudes; XXI"; Film Negative marked, "Nature of Internal Friction; plot containing points from W.P. Mason's work; XXI"; Notes and graphs marked, "Coordinated data; Internal Friction Studies; XXI"; Drawings marked, "Internal Friction Apparatus Shop Drawings; XXI"; Notes and Drawings marked, "Oscillatory Viscosimeter Shop Drawings; Internal Friction Studies; XXI"; Graphs marked, "Internal Friction Coordinated Data; XXI"; Graphs marked, "Plotted Internal Friction Data; Sand in Steel Tube; XXI"
  - Section of Files entitled, XXII The Broader Scope of the Stokes Wave Equation. Contains prints of charts and diagrams, and computer printouts., 238180 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Items in folder: Graphs marked, "Extrapolations to Large Distances and Large Charges."; Graphs marked, "Extrapolation to teleseismic distances and Megaton Charge Sizes; Displacement - E. P. Velocity and E. P. Acceleration vs. Travel Time. Pierre shale graphs drawn on Laws of Wavelet Propagation and extended to teleseismic distances and to charges in megaton range."; Notes marked, "IBM card programme computer."; Notes marked, "Wavelet Functions Calculated on Friden Calculator"
  - Section of Files entitled, Reflection Theory. Contains prints of diagrams and charts., 238177 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Items in folder: Notes marked, "Reflection and Refraction Theory."; Notes marked, "The Reflection of Seismic Wavelets; Reflections Computations Theory"
  - Section of Files entitled, Special Seismic Studies. Prints of Charts and diagrams., 238171 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Items in folder: Notes and graph marked, "Theory of Reflection Point Migration."; Graphs marked, "Special Studies; Numerical Distance of Form vs. Depth of Shot; Limon and Last Chance, Colo."; Graphs marked, "Early Studies; Amplitude vs. Travel Time; made with Conventional Amplifiers"; Film Negative marked, "Spectrum of Wavelet Complexes"; Graphs marked, "Travel time of Wavelet Center Experimental Data"
  - Correspondence and (unidentified) photographs from Sam Zimmerman., 238170 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of mathematical calculations on a blackboard., n.d; 238169 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Reprint of How Fast Does Glass Crack? Author unknown. Technology Review, Nov. 1938.; 238168 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Notes of Laws of Wavelet Propagation., n.d.; 238167 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Notebook entitled, Set of Figures to Accompany Ten Lectures on The Wavelet Theory of Seismogram Structure., October 1947.; 238166 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Spiral notebook containing handwritten lecture notes. Entitled, Wavelet Contraction, wavelet expansion, and the control of seismic resolution., 238165 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Spiral notebook containing handwritten lecture notes and photographs. Entitled, On the Form and Nature of Seismic Waves and the Structure of Seismograms., 238164 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Notebook containing typewritten lecture notes. Entitled, The Wavelet Theory of Seismogram Structure. Houston, TX., Oct. 1947.; 238163 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Spiral notebook containing handwritten lecture notes. Entitled, The Form of a Seismic Disturbance Due to an Explosion, Houston, TX., Nov. 1947.; 238162 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Spiral notebook, containing handwritten lecture notes and photographs. Entitled, On the Form and Nature of Seismic Waves and the Structure of Seismograms., 238161 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Prints of Charts and Diagrams, 238160 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Photographic Print of a Graph., n.d.; 238159 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Notebook containing prints, entitled, The Primary Seismic Disturbance., n.d.; 238158 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Prints concerning wavelet theory., n.d.; 238150 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Items in folder: Graphs marked, "Hi-pass Amplifiers for admore studies to see if signal level / noise level is satisfactory."; Notes marked, "Typewritten Copies of Various Reports"; Photographic Print marked, "Wavelet Theory"; Film Negatives marked, "Wavelet Theory"; Photographic Prints marked, "Miscellaneous Prints, some duplicates of figures in book"; Photographic Prints marked, "Miscellaneous Prints of minor importance"; Graphs marked, "Wavelets"
  - Notebook containing handwritten notes. Entitled, Theory of Reflection Point Migration., 238149 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Copy of a Russian academic journal containing a review of one of Ricker's articles. Moscow, 1978.; 238148 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Paper entitled, The Reflection of the Primary Dilatational Disturbance from the Base of the Low Velocity Layer., n.d.; 238147 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Prints and graphs dealing with wavelet theory., 238142 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Items in folder: Notes marked, "Suggestions for Future Wavelet Theory Development"; Notes marked, "Theory of Reflection Pt. Migration"; Paper and notes marked, "A Scale of Amplitudes for use in Seismic Prospecting"; Notes and graph marked, "Theory of Wavelet Contraction with a Tuned Resonant Seismograph"
  - Notebook containing handwritten notes. Entitled, The Reflection of Seismic Wavelets., 238141 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Typewritten pages of a manuscript, marked, Chapters 17, 18, and 19., 238140 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Notes marked, Miscellaneous Notes on Wavelet Theory; Paper for MAC., n.d.; 238139 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Typewritten pages of a manuscript, marked, Chapters 17, 18, and 19. Eliminated from book., 238138 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Bound notebook containing handwritten draft of Wavelet Contraction and Seismic Resolving Power., 238137 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Contract with Dutch publisher, 16 July 1976.; 238136 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Prints of charts and diagrams, marked Figures removed from manuscript chapters 17, 18, 19., 238135 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Handwritten outlines for a book entitled, The Propagation of Transient Elastic Disturbances in Solid Bodies and in Granular Media., 238134 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Memoranda and notes concerning wavelet functions., 19 August 1953.; 238133 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Recording of lecture entitled, Wavelet Contraction, Wavelet Expansion, and the Control of Seismic Resolution. Presented before Geophysical Society of Tulsa, Midwestern Regional Meeting of S. E. G. at Ft. Worth, and before the annual convention of S. E. G. at Houston, 25 March 1953.; 238132 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Notes entitled, Research Plans., August 1946.; 238131 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Photographic negative of seismic graphs., n.d.; 238130 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Graphs entitled, Normal Gravity Anomalies of the earth., n.d.; 238129 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Prints and negatives of diagrams, charts, graphs and calculations concerning seismic research., 238119 (Box 11, Folder 17)